A Guide to the Abraham Pais papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA014
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1895-1999; 3; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  - Yang, C. N. - Introduction to High Energy Physics, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
- Lectures, 1945-1996; 4; 0.5 Cubic Feet
  This series contains handwritten and typed copies of lectures presented by Pais. The series also includes some lecture related correspondence and advertisements for the lectures.
  - Advanced Quantum Mechanics (Field Theory) - Columbia University, Winter 1955-1956 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Astrophysics, undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Balfour Lectures, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - "Continuous Groups and Reflections in Quantum Mechanics" - by W. Pauli (Lectures 1-28), 1958 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Dispersion Relations, June 1959 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Field Theory - Columbia University, Spring 1955 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Freeman Dyson, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Heinz Rudolph Pagels, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Helen Dukas, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Multipion Systems Lecture (Bounds etc.), 1963, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Petiau, G. - Lectures, 1945-1956; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Petiau, G. - Lectures, 1945-1956; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Planck Lecture - NY Copy, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - The Power of the Word, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - RU "Popular Lecture", undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - X-Rays and Radium Lecture, undated (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1957-1959 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1960-1964 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1965-1967 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1968-1988 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1941-2000; 5; 1.7 Cubic Feet
  This series contains both personal and professional correspondence, both typed and handwritten. Some correspondents include Niels Bohr, the CERN facility, Helen Dukas, the Institute of Advanced Study, Hans Kramers, the National Academy of Sciences, George Uhlenbeck and Leon Rosenfeld.
  - A (Aaserud - Auburn), undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - B (Baker - Brown), undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Berkeley, 1956-1963 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Berlin, 1982-1990 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Biodata - Others, 1980-1982 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Bohr, A., 1946-1979 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Bohr Memorial, 1962-1963 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Bohr, N. - Reminiscences, 1954-1984 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Bohr, Professor N., 1947-1982 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Books, 1979-1981 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Breit, C., 1946-1967 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Bronk, Dr. Detlev W., 1963-1970 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - C (Carnegie - Curie), undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Car, 1968-1987 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - CERN, 1955-1979 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - China, 1982-1987 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Cohen, E. G. D., 1975-1997 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Columbia University, 1954-1968 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Cool, R., 1966-1970 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Coral Gables, 1979-1980 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1980-1982 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Crack-pot File, 1947-1987 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - D (Dalitz - Dyson), undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Dubna, M. S., 1964 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Dukas, Helen, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Dyson, Dr. Freeman, 1949-1971 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - E (Ehrenfest - Extermann), undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Einstein Collected Works, 1984-1993 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Electronic Nobel Museum (ENM), 1999 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - F (Feinberg - Fulton), undated (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1951-1953 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1954 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1955-1956 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1956-1957 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1958-1959 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1959-1960 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1960-1962 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Faculty - IAS [Institute for Advanced Study], 1962 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - F.B.I., 1981-1999 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - FOM [Foundation for Fundamental Research of Matter], 1975 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - G (Garrison - Gursey), undated (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - "The Genius of Science", 1999-2000 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - H (Ha - Hulthn), undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - House, 1978-1989 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - I (Immigration & Naturalization - Italie), undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, 1945-1954 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, 1959, 1962-1963 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Insurance, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - [Isotopic Spin], 1950-1952 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Israel, 1976-1977 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - J (Japan - Judge), undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Japan, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Jost, Res., 1972-1985; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Jost, Res., 1972-1985; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - K (Kac - Kuiper), undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Ke [subscript 4], 1967-1968 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Khuri, Dr. N. N., 1963-1968 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Knickerbocker Club, 1978-1986 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Koch, Congressman E., 1969 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Kramers, H. A., 1943-1952 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - L (Lamb - Lyons), undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Lederberg, 1960, 1965, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Lee & Yang, 1949-1958 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Life Energies, 1970-1971 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - M (Manneback - Munksgaard), undated (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Michel, Louis, 1952-1965 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Montpeirous, Raymonde, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Moscow, 1955-1959 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - MRS [Model, Roland, and Stone], 1960-1962 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - N (National Arts Club - Nobel Symposia), undated (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1962-1963 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - National Science Foundation & Dept. of the Air Force, 1967-1968 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - New York, 1964-1965 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Nordic Institute, undated (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - O (Oehme - Omni), undated (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Oppenheimer Prize, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - P (Panofsky - Purcell), undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Pagels, H. R., 1966-1968, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Pais, L. [Lila], undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Pauli Correspondence, 194[?]-1963 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Permission Granted, 1990-1993 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Pictures, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Princeton, 1977-1979 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Princeton Visiting Committee, 1980-1987 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - R (Rabi - Ruderman), undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Rntgen, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Rosenfeld, L., 1941-1966 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - S (Sakarov - Synge), undated (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Salary, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Sanda, A., 1974-1991 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - "SLAC", 1968-1984 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Smithsonian, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Stockholm, 1982-1998 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - T (Talmi - Treiman), undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Travel, 1948-1960 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - U (Ufford - Utiyama), undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - USSR, 1965-1974 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - V (Van Hove - Villars), undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Veltman, 1966-1975 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Von Neumann, 1949-1992 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - W (Waller - Wu), undated (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Weisskopf, Victor, 1981-1984 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Y (Yang - Yukawa), undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Z (Zanstra - ZWO), undated (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 58, Folder 12)
- Notes and Notebooks, 1935-1982; 6; 4.6 Cubic Feet
  This series contains bound notebooks and loose notes written by Pais from his time attending university until his professorship at the Rockefeller University. Most of the notes are subject based such as composite particles, field theory, mesons, particle theory, strong interactions and structure problems. There are a number of notebooks that are undated and unlabeled in regards to content.
  - Calc Post V., 1951 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - CERN - Geneva 23 Switzerland, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - CERN Lectures, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Colliding Beams, 1957-1970 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Columbia, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Composite Particles - Stanford, August 1951 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Conform _____ [2nd word illegible], undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Cosmic Rays, 1938-1939 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Covariance Problems, undated (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - CP, 1958-1973; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - CP, 1958-1973; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Damping Problems, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Differentiaal - Meetkunde, 1937-1938 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Essays, 1958-1982 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Field Theory, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Field Theory, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Field Theory II, 1948-1949 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    Strong Coupling
  - Field Theory III, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Field Theory Notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Field Theories with Non-Localized Action - I, undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Formularium, undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Functie Theorie, 1938-1939 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Helicity, undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Helium I & II, 1941 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - [History of Atomic Structure], undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - History of Physics, 1947-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Hydrodynamics, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Inclusive Reactions, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Institute for Advanced Study - I, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Integ[rnabubeuing] - Professor Wolff, 1938-1939 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - ISING - Model, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Ising Model - Calculations - Stanford, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Isospin Bounds, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - JETPL, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Klasnike Electroneutheorie - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - LCA, 1971-1972 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Many Body Problems I - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Many Body Problems II - Institute for Advanced Study, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Many Body Problems III - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Maxwell - Ref. Chap. 1, 1855-1904, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1)
    Undated notes.
  - Mesons, Mass Spectra, Non-Localizable Systems - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Models, 1967-1975 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Neutral Currents; Heavy Leptons, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Niels Bohr, 1986-1987 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Non-Leptonic Decays, 1957, 1960-1961 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Non-Localized Fields - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Strong Coupling Theory, undated (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Notes 76 - Rockefeller University, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Nuclear Physics III, Jost - Pais Calculations - Institute for Advanced Study, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Nuclear Theory I - Institute for Advanced Study - Course, 1948-1949 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear Theory II - Institute for Advanced Study, 1948-1949 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Particles I - Institute for Advanced Study, 1953-1954 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Particles II - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Particles III - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Particles IV - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Particles V - Institute for Advanced Study, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Pi, undated (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Polaron - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Potential Scattering - Rockefeller Institute, undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Q Quant, undated (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Recent Varia, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Relativiteits - Theorie, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - R Poles, undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Seminars Etc., undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - SSGLA, undated (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Statistical Mechanics I, 1935-1936 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Statistical Mechanics II, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Statistics Problems - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Strong Interactions (Institute for Advanced Study), 1963 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Structure of Hadronic Currents, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Structure Problems I - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Structure Problems II - Institute for Advanced Study, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Structure Problems III - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Structure Problems IV - Institute for Advanced Study, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Structure Problems V - Institute for Advanced Study, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Structure Problems VI, 1955 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - SU(6), 1964 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Symm. Pscalar Theory - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Theorie tan Dirac, 1937-1938; [Fragile] (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Thermodynamica, undated (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Varia, undated (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Varia, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Varia, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Vector Meson Theory, undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Weak Interactions - Institute for Advanced Study, undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Weak Interactions II, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - I, undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - II, 1960 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - 8 eqn, undated (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1936] (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1936-1937] (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1936-1937] (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1938-1939] (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1944] (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1956-1957] (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1963-1966] (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1962] (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - [Untitled Notes], [1962-1970] (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - [Untitled Notes], [1962-1977] (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - [Untitled Notes], [1963-1970] (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled Notebook], [1964-1970] (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - [Untitled Notes], [1972] (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled Notes 1], undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled Notes 2], undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - [Untitled Notes 3], undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled Notebook 4], undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled Notebook 5], undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - [Untitled Notebook 6], undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled Notebook 7], undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled Notebook 8], undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - [Untitled Notebook 9], undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled Notebook 10], undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - [Untitled Notebook 11], undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - [Untitled Notebook 12], undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - [Untitled Notebook 13], undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled Notebook 14], undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - [Untitled Notebook 15], undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled Notebook 16], undated (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled Notebook 17], undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - [Untitled Notebook 18], undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled Notebook 19], undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - [Untitled Notebook 20], undated (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - [Untitled Notebook 21], undated (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - [Untitled Notebook 22], undated (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - [Untitled Notebook 23], undated (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - [Untitled Notebook 24], undated (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - [Untitled Notebook 25], undated (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - [Untitled Notebook 26], undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled Notebook 27], undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Pais Photos, 1920-1997; 7; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  Arranged by type and alphabetically.
  This series is divided firstly by the type of media and includes photo prints and negatives, slides, glass slides and photo albums. Most of these are personal photos from Pais' childhood, family and travels. There are also professional photos for publication and publicity purposes, conference photos and lecture slides. There are also three artifacts within this series that were included in the folders with the photos; they are a menorah tie tack and two cloth stars of David belonging to Pais and his father. The artifacts, photo albums and framed photos have been placed in separate flat boxes.
  Photographs
  - Autobiography Material, 1937-1960 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Autobiography - Originals, circa 1928-1997 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Autobiography Pictures, circa 1928-1988 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - [Child Holding a Ball], undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - [Children Playing on Steps], undated (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Family Pictures, 1953-1956, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Dubna, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Einstein Book Pictures, 1930, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Pictures, 1940, 1948, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Cloth Star of David - J. Pais, undated (Box 075A, Folder 1)
  - Metal Menorah Tie Tack, undated (Box 075B, Folder 1)
  - Cloth Star of David - J. Pais, undated (Box 075A, Folder 1)
  - Metal Menorah Tie Tack, undated (Box 075B, Folder 1)
  - Family Pictures, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Family Photos, 1962, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Fermilab National Accelerator Laboratory, undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - [Framed Photo of Cabin], undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - [Framed Photo of Pais], undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - The Genius of Science - Photos, 1920-1997 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Holland, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - International Congress on Theoretical Physics - University of Washington, September 1956 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Jamaica, undated (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Japanese Artifacts, 1957 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - [Loose Photos], 1946-1958 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Michigan - Rochester Collaboration 405GeV Proton-Proton Interaction in the 30-inch Hydrogen Bubble Chamber at National Accelerator Laboratory, May 1973 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - [Pais Portrait], undated (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Paul Dirac - Photographs, Royal Society Talk, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Personal - Josh at Beach, undated (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 1981, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, Personal, undated (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Photos from Trip to Soviet Union, undated (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Pictures, 1941-1994 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Pictures, 1997, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Pictures and Related Papers, 1920-1943, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Pictures & WWII Documents, 1935-1968, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Pictures Taken by Abraham Pais, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Pictures Taken by Abraham Pais in Russia and in (?), undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Pictures - 7th Annual Conference on High Energy Nuclear Physics, 1957 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - [Unidentified Portrait], undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - World War II, 1940's, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Einstein and Maja - Picture Negative Slide, 1930 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - [Loose Photos] - Negatives, 1946-1958 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Negatives for "Mesprofers d'avenir - Fig. 1", 1981 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Photo - Aorau, undated (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Personal (Negatives), 1982 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - [Unidentified Portrait] - Negative, undated (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Cloth Star of David, undated (Box 077A, Folder 1)
  - Cloth Star of David, undated (Box 077A, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album, 1932-1936 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album (Trip to France and Spain), 1952 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Pais Oversized Photos, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Union Trip Photos - Oversized, undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - 12th Solvay Conference (Framed Photo), October 1961 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Commemoration Meeting for Niels Bohr, Copenhagen (Framed Photo), July 1963 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Pictures (Including Family) - Negatives, undated (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Photos Taken Spring 2001 (Negatives Gallery), undated; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Photos Taken Spring 2001 (Negatives Gallery), undated; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #1-10, undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #11-20, undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #21-30, undated (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #31-40, undated (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #41-50, undated (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries] #51-58, undated (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - [Unlabeled Negatives] C-1, C-2, C-3 16140, undated (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - [Untitled Negatives] C-1 18973, undated (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - [Untitled Negatives] C-2 R24228, undated (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries], undated; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries], undated; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries], undated; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 84, Folder 15)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries], undated; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - [Untitled Negatives and Galleries], undated; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 84, Folder 17)
  - [Untitled and Unmatched Galleries], undated (Box 84, Folder 18)
  - [Untitled and Unmatched Galleries], undated (Box 84, Folder 19)
  - Slides - South of France, 1957; Box 1 of 4 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Slides - South of France, 1957; Box 2 of 4 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Slides - South of France, 1957; Box 3 of 4 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Slides - South of France, 1957; Box 4 of 4 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Slides - Paul Dirac, undated (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Slides - Inward Bound, undated (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Slides - A. Einstein and Sister, Maja, undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Slides - Guccstrand, undated (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Slides - Einstein Slides, undated (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Slides - Box 1 of 3, undated (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Slides - Box 2 of 3, undated (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Slides - Box 3 of 3, undated (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Slides - Unidentified, undated (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Glass Slides - 63-3267 A - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Glass Slides - 63-3267 B - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Glass Slides - 63-3267 C - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Glass Slides - 63-3267 D - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Glass Slides - 63-3267 E - Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #1, undated (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #2, undated (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3947 - Dr. Pais #3, undated (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #4, undated (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #5, undated (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #6, undated (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Glass Slides - 65-3909 - Dr. Pais #7, undated (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #1, undated (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #2, undated (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #3, undated (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #4, undated (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #5, undated (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #6, undated (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #7, undated (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #8, undated (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #9, undated (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Glass Slides - A. Pais #10, undated (Box 86, Folder 22)
  - Glass Slides - HEP-Ke [subscript 4] - 68-261 Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 23)
  - Glass Slides - HEP-Ke [subscript 4] - 68-261 Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 24)
  - Glass Slides - HEP-Ke [subscript 4] - 68-261 Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 25)
  - Glass Slides - HEP-Ke [subscript 4] - 68-261 Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 26)
  - Glass Slides - HEP-Ke [subscript 4] - 68-261 Dr. Pais, undated (Box 86, Folder 27)
  - Glass Slides - Mub 963 - March 1962 (Box 86, Folder 28)